[SPEAKER_06]: We drove up to Pittsburgh on Friday afternoon, leaving here about 1.30 and got into our motel about 5 in Brentwood.
[SPEAKER_06]: And we relaxed a while and finally went out for supper at Arby's and then over to Knetzer's.
[SPEAKER_06]: Got there about, just about on time, quarter to 8 or so in the evening.
[SPEAKER_06]: And left about quarter to 12.
[SPEAKER_06]: They were real nice to us, the Robinsons.
[SPEAKER_06]: Mr. Knutzer was just as interested as he could be.
[SPEAKER_06]: They thought, they tried to get him to go to bed a couple of times, but he kept not going to bed.
[SPEAKER_06]: He went upstairs once, they thought he was going to bed, but he grabbed his pipe and came back down and puffed his pipe.
[SPEAKER_06]: While I was taking pictures, or trying to take pictures with the 35mm camera.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well,
[SPEAKER_06]: Saturday morning we got up about 7.30 and had a leisurely breakfast and went looking for the bookstore, which was down the road a little bit, but it was not open until noon.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was raining and foggy on Saturday morning, yesterday morning.
[SPEAKER_06]: We're back home now, Sunday morning.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'm filling up this side of the tape.
[SPEAKER_06]: We decided to go back to
[SPEAKER_06]: Robinsons because there's a couple more pictures I thought I ought to get since we were up there now, get the main ones.
[SPEAKER_06]: There's Scrapbook Two I thought might be nice, a lot of good stories in there.
[SPEAKER_06]: And they were on size pages which could be easily xeroxed.
[SPEAKER_06]: So we stopped there about 9.30 or so at the Robinson's, but no sign of life.
[SPEAKER_06]: I didn't want to go waking everybody up, so we just forgot about it, went on over to Boone, which is where we had the appointment scheduled, and got there a little early, but sat in the car for a few minutes, and about quarter to ten we went on in.
[SPEAKER_06]: And they were ready for us, and we had a nice interview at Boone's.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I got, well, we left there about a quarter after 12.
[SPEAKER_06]: I taped about an hour and a half, and I showed him the pictures I had copied, returned those that I'd borrowed, and promised to make prints of any of those that he would like to have copies of for his children, or for kids sending him for autographs to give him some extra copies.
[SPEAKER_06]: So he's going to look over the list,
[SPEAKER_06]: see what he has there, what I have that he would like to have.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then I took about 20 or 25 pictures with the 35mm camera, about 20, I guess.
[SPEAKER_06]: We'd taken about 10 over at Knetzler's, and we took about 20 more.
[SPEAKER_06]: I think I had 32 taken by the time we left the place.
[SPEAKER_06]: from the scrapbook and a few odd ones.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he gave me a pile of pictures to copy, some huge ones.
[SPEAKER_06]: And they wouldn't even fit in that big cardboard container I had for the big pictures.
[SPEAKER_06]: So I had them all scattered about here in the house now, trying to get copies made.
[SPEAKER_06]: We got instructions from Luke Boone how to get over to Aetna on the north side of Pittsburgh to interview Ralph Michaels with whom we had an interview scheduled at about 2 o'clock, 2.30.
[SPEAKER_06]: He gave us very good instructions and we went back to the motel.
[SPEAKER_06]: Got there about 1, changed clothes because we didn't want to be, we wanted to be comfortably attired for the afternoon and then the drive back home.
[SPEAKER_06]: So we changed clothes and
[SPEAKER_06]: loaded the car up and got away from the Brentwood Motor Lodge in Brentwood there about 1.30 and drove back much of the way we came into Brentwood, crossed over the tri-river bridge or something a little bit west of the center of Pittsburgh,
[SPEAKER_06]: You could look across and see three river stadiums we crossed over.
[SPEAKER_06]: And this put us on the north side of the Ohio.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then we wound our way along Ohio Street and worked our way out to Hettner, which we reached about, oh, 10 after 2, a quarter after 2.
[SPEAKER_06]: Took us about 45 minutes from the motel.
[SPEAKER_06]: There wasn't too much traffic.
[SPEAKER_06]: We avoided the center of town.
[SPEAKER_06]: The weather had cleared a little bit.
[SPEAKER_06]: It wasn't raining and foggy anymore.
[SPEAKER_06]: It came patches of sunshine.
[SPEAKER_06]: We were listening to Buzsorgsky's Boris Gudunov on the way, by the way, in Metropolitan Opera.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, we got into Etna, and it was a tangled of narrow, hilly, windy, cobblestone streets.
[SPEAKER_06]: We couldn't quite find out where we were going.
[SPEAKER_06]: We got in wrong way streets going down steep hills.
[SPEAKER_06]: one-way streets going, up steep hills, it all twisted around.
[SPEAKER_06]: We finally found the place, Michael's house at 123 Locust Street, right across from the Elks Club.
[SPEAKER_06]: Michael had told me that if, to park right in front of the house there, and then to come over and see him in the Elks Club if he wasn't home.
[SPEAKER_06]: And so that's what I did.
[SPEAKER_06]: He went to the house, nobody there, and then went over to the Elks Club,
[SPEAKER_06]: After I got downstairs and got caught up in a teenage bowling congress, I went upstairs and pressed a button and waited for about ten minutes.
[SPEAKER_06]: Finally, a woman came and let me in.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then I went to the check, or wherever you check your coats at, that counter.
[SPEAKER_06]: And the guy said, yeah, he was in at the bar drinking beer.
[SPEAKER_06]: So he'd take me in there, so he took a few more minutes, finally I got in there.
[SPEAKER_06]: Michael was at the bar with a lot of other people watching the basketball game on television.
[SPEAKER_06]: And right away he told me he wasn't going to be interviewed.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was a big disappointment.
[SPEAKER_06]: He told me to come on up and to see him, and yeah.
[SPEAKER_06]: He wouldn't mind.
[SPEAKER_06]: At least that was the impression I got.
[SPEAKER_06]: There were one or two things he said when I talked to him on the phone last Monday that indicated he might not want to talk about this or that, but I at no time got the feeling he was going to clam up completely.
[SPEAKER_06]: But no sooner had he walked over from the bar, behind the bar, that he talked to me than I got right over.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was pleasant enough, but
[SPEAKER_06]: He wasn't going to be interviewed.
[SPEAKER_06]: No way would he be interviewed, especially on tape.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, which took me by surprise completely, and for a moment it looked as if he was just going to go right back to the bar and dismiss me on the spot, and that would be the end of it.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was pleasant enough in all of this,
[SPEAKER_06]: but very firm.
[SPEAKER_06]: He kept telling me he's a police chief for 17 years.
[SPEAKER_06]: This was old stuff way back there.
[SPEAKER_06]: He didn't want to remember it or bring it back.
[SPEAKER_06]: I never could quite pin it down what the reason was.
[SPEAKER_06]: He said he'd called Luke Boone earlier in the week and talked to him, checking up on me.
[SPEAKER_06]: He thought a lot about this, and he just decided he didn't want to be interviewed.
[SPEAKER_06]: He'd lost his wife and his sister a couple years ago, three losses right in a row.
[SPEAKER_06]: His life is kind of up in the air, I gather.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had a good reputation to maintain.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had a good reputation as a policeman.
[SPEAKER_06]: He didn't want anything to happen.
[SPEAKER_06]: He seemed to feel that by being interviewed on tape there was going to be some damage to his reputation, his career.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was just difficult to nail down specifically what his thoughts were, other than just a general distrust of tape recorders, which you get from time to time.
[SPEAKER_06]: He said he'd been in trouble about this upcoming visit of mine all week, and he just decided he wasn't going to be in it.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, he did loosen up a little bit and talk to me behind, next to the bar there, and he became quite expansive and confidential, and after each story he'd tell, he'd say, this was a great story, this should be on tape, and then he'd back off again while he was going back to the bar and dismiss me again.
[SPEAKER_06]: Every time I seemed to indicate that these were great stories and should be preserved for posterity while he was
[SPEAKER_06]: right away on his toes about to, right away on the brink of cutting me off.
[SPEAKER_06]: We chatted there about 20-25 minutes, I suppose, telling stories and good stories.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I was listening and gaining his confidence as we went along, I could see that.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then he got his wallet out and showed me pictures of himself as a police chief.
[SPEAKER_06]: Pictures of his wife who was in a bathing suit back in the vintage 1920s, 30s.
[SPEAKER_06]: She was quite a beautiful gal.
[SPEAKER_06]: I guess her loss was very, well, it's still bothering him.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had no children.
[SPEAKER_06]: At the end of the interview, he kept saying what a nice guy I was.
[SPEAKER_06]: much he appreciated my understanding, his not wanting to be interviewed.
[SPEAKER_06]: He thought what I was doing was great, wished me a lot of luck, but he just couldn't contribute himself.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he said I was a regular guy, and he was getting more chummy all the way along in that respect.
[SPEAKER_06]: And maybe if I had stayed with him longer and gotten Reedy in out of the car to help loosen him up a little bit, he might have been able to get something out of him.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was big and tough and outgoing and tough in a sense that if you pushed him, he'd react rather strongly.
[SPEAKER_06]: But he was a hale fellow, well-met chap.
[SPEAKER_06]: He knew everybody and talked loud and confidently and self-assuredly.
[SPEAKER_06]: He reminded me of a John Burnworth manner with an Ed Sherman look.
[SPEAKER_06]: He looks a lot like Ed Sherman, the Muskingum athletic director.
[SPEAKER_06]: His physical appearance is big, about six foot probably.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he's probably doesn't weigh anymore now.
[SPEAKER_06]: He's in his playing ball, 185 pounds, good build, no stomach, good features.
[SPEAKER_06]: He's got his hair, light gray hair, or dark gray hair.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well-lined but well-shaped face.
[SPEAKER_06]: dark sport of brown slacks and a brown jacket.
[SPEAKER_06]: I had one of those brown t-shirts, not a t-shirt, a dress t-shirt, perhaps, underneath, maybe a turtleneck, I've forgotten now.
[SPEAKER_06]: I mean, he looked in good shape and he was very jovial and so on, but I wasn't going to get an interview, a really detailed interview.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, here's some of the few things I did get.
[SPEAKER_06]: Let me light my cigar again.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's already lit.
[SPEAKER_06]: He came up in 1921, and I didn't really, I should have, but I didn't get his outline of his career.
[SPEAKER_06]: He came up in 21, or he came into baseball.
[SPEAKER_06]: I don't know who he was with.
[SPEAKER_06]: Apparently he was pirate property, however.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was with the pirates in spring training in 1923.
[SPEAKER_06]: And it looked like he might be able to start at shortstop that year.
[SPEAKER_06]: Whether it was McKechnie who was, he'd be beating out or not, I've forgotten.
[SPEAKER_06]: I didn't really pay too much attention.
[SPEAKER_06]: I was so disappointed not getting interviewed at this point.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was rooming with Ky-Ky Kyler there in training at Pittsburgh, and word came that Kyler was going to be shipped to Nashville for more season.
[SPEAKER_06]: And Michaels wanted to go with Kyler.
[SPEAKER_06]: He liked him, and he thought maybe he wasn't quite ready for the big time.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was coming up too fast, so he liked Kyler.
[SPEAKER_06]: talking around how he would like to go to Nashville.
[SPEAKER_06]: And McKechnie somehow, and I'm not clear what happened to him, McKechnie said something about, well, he would help arrange for his going to Nashville if he wanted to, and could get him a lot more money with Nashville than he had been contracted for with Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_06]: And this is the way it worked out.
[SPEAKER_06]: He got twice as much.
[SPEAKER_06]: I don't know the exact amounts now.
[SPEAKER_06]: It must sound like a pretty good pay at Nashville.
[SPEAKER_06]: And so he spent the 1923 season in Nashville.
[SPEAKER_06]: I haven't checked these up in the guides.
[SPEAKER_06]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he said also, I think I got McKechnie was on a spot here because I was rumored I was starting his place there.
[SPEAKER_06]: He wanted to, whether McKechnie was managing the team then, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_06]: This is all kind of confusing, but he said something about getting McKechnie off the spot by his going to Nashville and easing the situation down there in Pitchford.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, after the 23 season, and I don't know what he did there, he came back up, and this was the year he gave Kaikai Cotter his name.
[SPEAKER_06]: He told me that on the phone.
[SPEAKER_06]: Kyler was playing center field for Nashville, and Michaels was shortstop, and the five balls were one direct hit to the outfield.
[SPEAKER_06]: He would have a short center relay to throw, and he'd yell, Ky, Ky.
[SPEAKER_06]: He'd throw it for Kyler, and they heard it up in the press box, I guess.
[SPEAKER_06]: One of the reporters, Horn, I think his name was,
[SPEAKER_06]: I asked him, what are you calling Kyler out there?
[SPEAKER_06]: He said, I'm not calling him, I'm just yelling Ky, Ky.
[SPEAKER_06]: I said, well that's what it's going to be from now on, he's Ky, Ky, Kyler.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's the story he told me about.
[SPEAKER_06]: Kyler never threw the ball into him, he always threw it way over his head into the home plate.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had such a good arm I guess, but he was out there yelling at him anyhow.
[SPEAKER_06]: That supposedly is how Kyler got his nickname.
[SPEAKER_06]: They came back up to
[SPEAKER_06]: Pittsburgh, either the end of the year or during the winter, and Dreyfus, the Pirate Manor owner, offered Michaels for the 24th season the same salary he'd offered him for 1923, which would be a cut from what he got at Nashville.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he became quite uncooperative, as Michaels did.
[SPEAKER_06]: As he said himself, he's quite chesty.
[SPEAKER_06]: He sure was.
[SPEAKER_06]: He's a little belligerent there.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he said to Dreyfus, why should I take this cut in pay from what I've been getting down at Nashville?
[SPEAKER_06]: And maybe I should be traded or something, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was getting a little uppity.
[SPEAKER_06]: And Dreyfus said, Michael said, Dreyfus said, in his Jewish way, he said, well, maybe you speak too soon, something like that.
[SPEAKER_06]: that he was getting a little too impetuous about what he wanted and what he was going to do.
[SPEAKER_06]: He should be more patient about higher pay.
[SPEAKER_06]: So it's a little unclear.
[SPEAKER_06]: Somebody was outside the room, I heard this, and there was a scout for some other club,
[SPEAKER_06]: He said, well, do you want to go someplace else?
[SPEAKER_06]: I said, Michael, yeah, I'd like to.
[SPEAKER_06]: At any rate, he went to Wichita Falls, he was shipped to Wichita Falls in the Texas League for some training, whether this was meaning the Pirates weren't going to use him or what, it isn't clear, but they were playing the Chicago Cubs coming back from Catalina.
[SPEAKER_06]: in spring training 24, I believe it was, and the Cubs played the Wichita Falls team.
[SPEAKER_06]: Grover Cleveland Alexander was pitching for the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_06]: He'd just been acquired with Killefer from the Phillies.
[SPEAKER_06]: A $100,000 battery, and Michael said, a $100,000 battery, a great battery.
[SPEAKER_06]: You know what a battery is, pitcher and catcher?
[SPEAKER_06]: If I didn't know what a battery was.
[SPEAKER_06]: He says, Alexander's pitching, you know, I got three hits off Alexander in that game.
[SPEAKER_06]: And after the game, he came to me and said, Mike, you want to go back the big time?
[SPEAKER_06]: I said, well, who doesn't?
[SPEAKER_06]: He said, well, pack your bags.
[SPEAKER_06]: You've been sold.
[SPEAKER_06]: You've been traded to the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he said, you know who carried my bags to the station that night?
[SPEAKER_06]: Grover Cleveland Alexander.
[SPEAKER_06]: What on earth Grover Cleveland Alexander was doing carrying Ralph Michaels' bags to the railroad station, I'll never know.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I didn't find out.
[SPEAKER_06]: He kept referring to himself as a young punk, an immature young ball player, a little too chesty maybe.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had a realistic sense about his own value, I guess.
[SPEAKER_06]: But he was trainer of the Cubs for three players.
[SPEAKER_06]: The one I remember is Marty Callahan, an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_06]: But there's an infielder and a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_06]: And so that's how he went to the Cubs for the 1924 season.
[SPEAKER_06]: And the manager of the Cubs in those years was
[SPEAKER_06]: I think Moranville, Killefer, and McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_06]: One each one, a different one each year.
[SPEAKER_06]: We never did talk much about his career in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_06]: It wasn't convenient to talk much about anything in those circumstances.
[SPEAKER_06]: I was still thinking of some way to try to get him to be interviewed by tape.
[SPEAKER_06]: He kept talking about these stories.
[SPEAKER_06]: Maybe I could just see him sometime without a tape or anything.
[SPEAKER_06]: Let him talk about these stories and try to remember them and tape them afterwards.
[SPEAKER_06]: Now... What else here?
[SPEAKER_06]: Yeah, he was with Kansas City in the later 20s.
[SPEAKER_06]: In fact, he was with them when they won the American Association pennant in the Little World Series, the Junior World Series in 1929.
[SPEAKER_06]: Pretty tough team there.
[SPEAKER_06]: I checked up on the guy last night, so they had a picture of the Kansas City team, and there he was.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he showed me from his wallet a little wallet-sized card
[SPEAKER_06]: which apparently all of the members of the Kansas City Club carried in 1929, mentioning their name and identifying the club and something about the club.
[SPEAKER_06]: And on the back side of it was a little picture of the player himself.
[SPEAKER_06]: He carries this in his wallet still.
[SPEAKER_06]: He also carried in his wallet a card of a pass for his wife for all the Junior World Series games.
[SPEAKER_06]: I believe that's what it was.
[SPEAKER_06]: So that was in very good condition.
[SPEAKER_06]: He said this was the only one they gave out or something like that.
[SPEAKER_06]: I don't know quite why that would be the case.
[SPEAKER_06]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_06]: At Kansas City, Spencer Abbott was the manager, I guess, and they were teammates.
[SPEAKER_06]: Lute Boone and Ralph Michaels were teammates there at Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_06]: Michael Boone got into an awful fight with Spencer Abbott.
[SPEAKER_06]: I think this is on my first Luke Boone tape, which explains why he was with Kansas City just a short time and was then traded off to Louisville or maybe Louisville.
[SPEAKER_06]: But he got in this fight with Spencer Abbott.
[SPEAKER_06]: Michael was on the team then, and Michael said that the
[SPEAKER_06]: When I'm talking to him yesterday, he says, uh, this, uh, I had to step in between those two.
[SPEAKER_06]: That was quite a fight, you know.
[SPEAKER_06]: I wanted him to really get on it all, to that effect.
[SPEAKER_06]: So, uh, Boone never liked Spencer Abbott.
[SPEAKER_06]: So when Michaels called up Lute Boone this week to check up on me, see what kind of credentials I had, and Lute Boone answered the phone, and Michaels says, hello, Lute, this is Spencer Abbott.
[SPEAKER_06]: And Ruth said, well, hello, Spencer.
[SPEAKER_06]: How are you?
[SPEAKER_06]: And Michael said, you old hypocrite.
[SPEAKER_06]: This is Ralph Michaels.
[SPEAKER_06]: Hello, Ralph.
[SPEAKER_06]: How are you?
[SPEAKER_06]: Same voice, same tone.
[SPEAKER_06]: He said, well, he's talking to Spencer Avedon.
[SPEAKER_06]: Spencer Avedon to me.
[SPEAKER_06]: So Michael saw that as a great joke.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's the kind of guy he was.
[SPEAKER_06]: He's good.
[SPEAKER_06]: Because he'd be a terrific police chief.
[SPEAKER_06]: Outgoing.
[SPEAKER_06]: Not a bit shy.
[SPEAKER_06]: Good sense of humor.
[SPEAKER_06]: Knows everybody.
[SPEAKER_06]: Of course, Spence Rabbit's been dead about 20 years.
[SPEAKER_06]: I guess neither of them knew it.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's all I can tell.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, anything else here that came out of that?
[SPEAKER_06]: Any stories worth telling?
[SPEAKER_06]: No, I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_06]: I could have talked more to him and gotten a few stories, but I was pretty disgusted anyhow.
[SPEAKER_06]: Since we weren't going to be able to get a good interview, we might as well drive back on home, get home before dark.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was then around three o'clock, probably.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'm not sure how
[SPEAKER_06]: how accurate some of the things he said would be.
[SPEAKER_06]: He might be prone to exaggeration, but I'm sure he would have had some good stories, and I'm very disappointed we didn't get through to him.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, we walked on out to the main lobby.
[SPEAKER_06]: He wanted to get out with his better light to show me some pictures in his wallet.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's when we looked at the pictures of his wife.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he introduced me to people who went along.
[SPEAKER_06]: One chap we met was a guy named Humminger, or Hummiger.
[SPEAKER_06]: And he said, boy, we used to have a great quartet.
[SPEAKER_06]: Apparently, Michael was a singer, too.
[SPEAKER_06]: And it reminded him of another story when he was with some team, whether it was the Kansas City Club, maybe, or one of the clubs he was with.
[SPEAKER_06]: They had a couple of other people who were pretty good singers.
[SPEAKER_06]: And they used to do a lot of singing as a group.
[SPEAKER_06]: And this got into the paper one time about all the harmony on this particular club.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then he chuckled and said, the harmony was our singing.
[SPEAKER_06]: That was the real harmony, not anything else.
[SPEAKER_06]: But that was a pretty good story.
[SPEAKER_06]: It probably was.
[SPEAKER_06]: But again, I wouldn't pay much attention to this thing.
[SPEAKER_06]: I was disgusted with the whole thing and ready to get out of there.
[SPEAKER_06]: So I didn't really take much note of what he was saying or try to get much more out of it.
[SPEAKER_06]: I probably could have, as I say.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'd have got a lot of data if I could remember it all.
[SPEAKER_06]: And maybe if Rita had been there, she would have remembered it.
[SPEAKER_06]: And maybe he would have sobbed up a bit.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I don't think he ever would have let the tape recorder go on, or even note-taking.
[SPEAKER_06]: I doubt whether he would have permitted that.
[SPEAKER_06]: As I say, I kind of debated him at first there to be, to prevent his just leaving me high and dry without anything, not even an explanation.
[SPEAKER_06]: But he warmed up a little bit, thought out.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was a, really a disappointment.
[SPEAKER_06]: The way he talked on the phone, in his loud, outgoing manner, a lot of stories.
[SPEAKER_06]: I was sure it was going to be one of my best interviews ever.
[SPEAKER_06]: I was just sure of this.
[SPEAKER_06]: So I can imagine the blow.
[SPEAKER_06]: It wasn't nothing at all.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, to finish up the day then, since there isn't much more to tell about Ralph Michaels on this tape, and the tape has got a long way to go, I'll describe our trip home and then talk about some of the
[SPEAKER_06]: pictures I got on this trip.
[SPEAKER_06]: We left Aetna, and after I got out of the alcohol, we wandered our way down those cobblestone winding streets and got out of there and worked our way back into town.
[SPEAKER_06]: It stopped raining by now.
[SPEAKER_06]: The sun was shining, but it was awfully muddy and mud splashing all over our windshield on the way.
[SPEAKER_06]: But we got out of Pittsburgh, okay, and
[SPEAKER_06]: Then it clouded up and started raining.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was on again, off again, all the rest of the way back.
[SPEAKER_06]: We stopped about five o'clock at the Dallas Pike Cherokee Inn there for supper, had a nice supper, and then resumed our way home.
[SPEAKER_06]: We arrived here about a quarter to seven.
[SPEAKER_06]: It got dark then.
[SPEAKER_06]: Rita drove from Dallas Pike and then it rained most of the way back in.
[SPEAKER_06]: Not heavy, but a steady, steady rain.
[SPEAKER_06]: We noticed at Dallas that the wind was blowing up, whipping up a storm there, but it seemed to die out and we didn't pay much more attention to it.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then, late last night, we listened to the news from Wheeling, which we'd gone right through about... No, I think we ate at Dallas about 4.15 to about 4.50 or so.
[SPEAKER_06]: We left there at Dallas Pike about 5 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_06]: unless we were going through Wheeling soon thereafter.
[SPEAKER_06]: But in the late news last night, the report was terrible windstorm and damage in the Wheeling area, especially along Route 7 east and west of Wheeling.
[SPEAKER_06]: High winds, 70 miles an hour, trailers turned over, trees blown down, power lines down.
[SPEAKER_06]: We didn't notice anything about that.
[SPEAKER_06]: We must have just gotten in ahead of it.
[SPEAKER_06]: Papers today tell about wind storms all the way along 70 and down 77 from Cambridge and throughout West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_06]: We had no knowledge of any of this.
[SPEAKER_06]: I think we just got in in time to miss most of it.
[SPEAKER_06]: But even so, there wasn't much down here at all last night.
[SPEAKER_06]: Our plan had been to perhaps stay over for last night in Pittsburgh, too, and pick up Gordon, who was flying into Pittsburgh Airport tonight.
[SPEAKER_06]: He was flying in today.
[SPEAKER_06]: We didn't know it would be tonight until, I think, Thursday.
[SPEAKER_06]: We'd hoped it would be in the morning.
[SPEAKER_06]: We could spend another night in Pittsburgh, maybe go to a hockey game last night, or perhaps have another interview somewhere.
[SPEAKER_06]: But when he said it was 9.30 at night he'd be coming in, especially after Michael's interview blew up, we just didn't hesitate.
[SPEAKER_06]: Had the Michael's interview been a good long one, a couple hours, and we'd gotten out of there around 5 or 5.30, it was getting dark and there was a wind in the rain, we thought we might just as well have gone back to our motel and stayed there another night.
[SPEAKER_06]: But since it had cleared up and the interview was no good, we just came on back home.
[SPEAKER_06]: A lot of things to do here anyway.
[SPEAKER_06]: We're gonna go back up to Pittsburgh this afternoon, this evening, and pick up Gordon.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's been snowing a little bit this morning, and the forecast is for clearing, I guess, later on today.
[SPEAKER_06]: So, we got home about 7 o'clock, and I spent the evening classifying, sorting, and repairing pictures which I'd gotten
[SPEAKER_06]: From the connoisseurs, I got one huge old poster.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's on rather thin, shiny paper.
[SPEAKER_06]: Must be about four feet long and a foot and a half high or so.
[SPEAKER_06]: 40 inches, 44 inches.
[SPEAKER_06]: I haven't measured it.
[SPEAKER_06]: Real long poster.
[SPEAKER_06]: with a big photograph, panoramic photograph in the center of Exposition Park, Pittsburgh, April 17.
[SPEAKER_06]: No, this is September 25, 1915.
[SPEAKER_06]: Just at the end of the Federal League season, Pittsburgh Rebels playing Newark.
[SPEAKER_06]: Eddie Rauch's Club at the end of the 1915 season.
[SPEAKER_06]: A big poster advertising the game with a photograph, a panoramic photograph of the park with a crowd in the stands and the game going on.
[SPEAKER_06]: And at the bottom, individual head shots of all the Pittsburgh players, including Elmer Knetzer.
[SPEAKER_06]: Now, this has been folded over center-wise into halves, quarter-wise, and then eighth-wise.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's been folded in that many places.
[SPEAKER_06]: The lines were torn.
[SPEAKER_06]: The edges were all chipped and roughed, a couple edges torn off.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was in pretty bad shape, although it was very clear.
[SPEAKER_06]: The condition of the paper was kind of bad, but the printing, everything was very clear.
[SPEAKER_06]: The pictures were nice and clear.
[SPEAKER_06]: So I repaired that.
[SPEAKER_06]: I ripped off some old
[SPEAKER_06]: scotch tape the head on the front of the thing, although not over any of the photographic part, over some of the printing.
[SPEAKER_06]: I got that off without too much damage and worked on the back side of it and I gradually scotch taped all the tears up.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then I taped on the back of the many seams, you know, so you couldn't fold it there, but then I rolled it, so it looks pretty good now.
[SPEAKER_06]: I think it'd be easy to photograph in sections, of course.
[SPEAKER_06]: You can't photograph, that's a huge thing.
[SPEAKER_06]: You have to photograph it in sections, and then maybe splice the sections together.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's a beautiful thing.
[SPEAKER_06]: Boy, I hope that comes out.
[SPEAKER_06]: There's another panoramic view of Exposition Park in Pittsburgh, April 17, 1915, opening day that same year, when Kansas City is in town.
[SPEAKER_06]: This is just a picture, there's no announcements, there's a little inscription at the bottom of what it is, but there's no individual pictures, there's no great big advertisement on top.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's kind of dark, but there is a
[SPEAKER_06]: good crowd, 17,000 in the stands.
[SPEAKER_06]: Both of these, the poster of September 25, 1915, and this photograph of April 17, 1915, are both taken from Centerfield.
[SPEAKER_06]: I guess the poster is from Deep Left Centerfield, and the photograph alone is from Deep Centerfield, the one of April 17.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's a little bit darker, and it may have trouble
[SPEAKER_06]: It may not be too clear when it's reproduced, but this, too, is a big one.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's not as big as the postage.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's maybe about 12 by 36, perhaps.
[SPEAKER_06]: But it's a nice big one.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's all rolled up.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was in good shape.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I hope that comes out.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then I got a little, a smaller reproduction from a newspaper photograph.
[SPEAKER_06]: of the Brooklyn Doggers of 1912, a teen picture.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's kind of green because it is a reproduction of a photograph.
[SPEAKER_06]: It was all rolled up and the paper wasn't very strong quality, kind of wrinkled.
[SPEAKER_06]: I flattened it out and mounted it on some cardboard.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I know when that's reproduced it'll be even fuzzier than it is now, but it's a pretty good picture anyhow, so I hope to reproduce that one.
[SPEAKER_06]: Those are the three of the biggest ones I got from Knutzer.
[SPEAKER_06]: There's one picture of Elmer Knutzer himself, maybe not quite 8x10, maybe 6x8 in uniform.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'm not sure what the uniform is.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's very faded, very light, very light.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's going to be awfully hard to do much with that, but I thought I'd bring it along and try anyhow.
[SPEAKER_06]: And one other picture is a teen picture of the 1932 Wilkes-Barre Barons with whom he played.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's a pretty good one.
[SPEAKER_06]: I hope that comes out well.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then I got some clippings, a couple of clippings.
[SPEAKER_06]: One story about the Robinson family at Palmer Commencement School, which they let me have because that's a duplicate.
[SPEAKER_06]: An article about the
[SPEAKER_06]: a Sunday magazine article about the Carrick Volunteers, with whom he played in 1904.
[SPEAKER_06]: A real tough semi-protein with a picture and a story.
[SPEAKER_06]: I could have that.
[SPEAKER_06]: They also gave me the original picture of the Carrick Volunteers, which I could have reproduced if I wanted, but I don't think I will because it'll cost money and it isn't that important.
[SPEAKER_06]: There's a good copy of it in the article and I think that will suffice.
[SPEAKER_06]: And there's another story about Knetzer's, it was interviewed just himself,
[SPEAKER_06]: I've forgotten the date on that, but it's when a younger man, the good sketch of his life.
[SPEAKER_06]: And they gave me a typed copy of his biography, about two-thirds of a page, single-space typing, which has the bare facts there, which I'm going to type myself, I think, make a copy of that.
[SPEAKER_06]: Those are the main items of condensers.
[SPEAKER_06]: Of course, I took about 10 or 12 pictures, photographs with my 35mm camera of the pictures in the scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_06]: He has a scrapbook, which is, as I mentioned earlier, I got some good
[SPEAKER_06]: stories in about his career, but it's mixed in with a lot of family pictures and an awful lot of clippings aren't even mounted, so I decided not to try to get that back and wait till Mrs. Robinson can remount the whole thing and include the ones that aren't mounted and separate them from the pictures, make a nice baseball scrapbook, and then maybe I can copy that.
[SPEAKER_06]: He had a lot of baseballs up there.
[SPEAKER_06]: Not many autographed ones.
[SPEAKER_06]: They had one, a Federal League ball, with the names of all the 1914 pit feds on them, but they weren't autographs.
[SPEAKER_06]: They were printed on.
[SPEAKER_06]: There were not a few other baseballs scattered around, but no autograph balls.
[SPEAKER_06]: I didn't make a pitch for any of those.
[SPEAKER_06]: I got Elmer Netscher to sign my autograph ball, which he did pretty well, although it was with a marking pen and kind of faded.
[SPEAKER_06]: And the night, Friday night after we got back to the motel, Rita inked it in better.
[SPEAKER_06]: Now over at Luke Boone's on Saturday morning, we got a huge picture of the 1920 St. Paul Saints, the club members sitting in civilian clothes, which he says was the best team he ever played for.
[SPEAKER_06]: I get that.
[SPEAKER_06]: We got the 1922 St. Paul Saints in a long panoramic view.
[SPEAKER_06]: They're all
[SPEAKER_06]: standing in a straight line, spread out, about 8 by 30 maybe, in front of the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_06]: I guess it's in the outfield, back against the outfield fence of the St. Paul Park.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'll have to find out more about that.
[SPEAKER_06]: The names of the players were not marked on the back.
[SPEAKER_06]: I spent a lot of time last night trying to figure out who they are.
[SPEAKER_06]: I got a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_06]: The 1920 St. Paul picture doesn't have the picked names either.
[SPEAKER_06]: Then he gave me the ticket for copying the 1926 Louisville Club, another big picture about 14 by 18 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_06]: He gave me to keep the 1929 Columbus Club because he had a second copy of that and I mounted that this morning.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's hanging up right over my head here.
[SPEAKER_06]: He gave me a little action shot where he tags out Bobby or
[SPEAKER_06]: Eddie Murphy at third base in a game between the Yankees and the White Sox in 1915.
[SPEAKER_06]: Bobby Wallace was the umpire.
[SPEAKER_06]: Vance Rollin, the third base coach.
[SPEAKER_06]: It's a nice little action shot which he had an extra copy of.
[SPEAKER_06]: He gave me for copying the 1916 New York Yankees a nice 8x10, very clear with names in it.
[SPEAKER_06]: for copying 1913 Dallas-Texas Club which was badly torn and the corners chipped off but pretty clear with some of the names inked in on the players' bodies.
[SPEAKER_06]: So I repaired that and I'm going to have that one copied.
[SPEAKER_06]: Four beautiful individual shots of Yankees of 1916.
[SPEAKER_06]: Ray Caldwell, Ray Keating, Cliff Markle, and Roy Hartso.
[SPEAKER_06]: Action shots on beautiful, white, glossy, heavy paper without any background at all.
[SPEAKER_06]: Just sole isolation.
[SPEAKER_06]: Looks like some of those pictures which might have been used in the front page of Sporting Life.
[SPEAKER_06]: We had just the action of the player himself with no background.
[SPEAKER_06]: Very clear and sharp, and that would be beautiful to reproduce.
[SPEAKER_06]: Those were all to be borrowed to be copied.
[SPEAKER_06]: I borrowed some fourteen pictures for copying, five from Knutzers and nine from the
[SPEAKER_06]: I think I mentioned all the 9 from Luke Bloom, Markle, Hartzell, Caldwell, Keating, 16 Yankees, 13 Dallas, 20 St. Paul, 22 St. Paul, 26 Louisville, Anselm Metzer, the 2 1915 Panorama Views of Exposition Park, 1912 Dallas Club, 1912 Dallas Club, 1912 Brooklyn Club, if I'm not mistaken.
[SPEAKER_06]: 1932 book by Wilkes-Barrell, and then Albert Nutz from South.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I got a couple more that they gave me.
[SPEAKER_06]: The two that Boone gave me.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, that was about it.
[SPEAKER_06]: I just checked through all the pictures.
[SPEAKER_06]: I got 14 pictures to copy.
[SPEAKER_06]: They're so big, many of them.
[SPEAKER_06]: It seems like an awful lot more, and it's going to be an expensive job.
[SPEAKER_06]: You're going to run out of money if you can do it at all.
[SPEAKER_06]: and the two pictures I got to keep that were surplus.
[SPEAKER_06]: I also told Luke Boone about the baseball guides and record books he has, and if he ever plans to dispose of them, if the family doesn't want them, to please let me know.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'd like a chance to have the first shot at them, and he was very agreeable to that.
[SPEAKER_06]: So it was all in all a very successful wear.
[SPEAKER_06]: Some good pictures, good interviews,
[SPEAKER_06]: except for Michael's was kind of a dud, but at least I talked to the guy and I got an interesting point of view.
[SPEAKER_06]: And that will be, you could write almost a chapter if I ever write a book on these interviews.
[SPEAKER_06]: A chapter on the psychology of these people not wanting to be interviewed or being interviewed.
[SPEAKER_06]: Some didn't want it, some didn't have any objection at all.
[SPEAKER_06]: The Netsers were very happy to have us there and they were pleased that we were interested in them.
[SPEAKER_06]: They were pleased that we were interested in them.
[SPEAKER_06]: I stopped back there Saturday to pick up the last couple of pictures and they told me that before Elman went to bed on Friday night after he left, he told them, he smiled at them, he said, they're nice people, they're nice people.
[SPEAKER_06]: And with that, there's no argument from this position, I think that's a good point to wrap up this tape on.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're welcome.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they ever have beer in the clubhouse after the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: Any managers permit that?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did the players go out to the tavern after a game for a beer or two, or was this okay with you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you've got a wonderful career in baseball here.
[SPEAKER_03]: What, uh, well, let's see here.
[SPEAKER_03]: When you played with Jeanette in the Middle Atlantic League,
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_04]: That's not very far away from here, is it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to take a car.
[SPEAKER_03]: I hope they could lock every back.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you live at home here?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's where I'm staying.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, that's your home?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's very short range.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it's about 16,000.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did you travel around in the, oh,
[SPEAKER_04]: In the Middle Atlantic League.
[SPEAKER_04]: I mean, when you played at home, you drove to Jeannette.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the other places, did you travel by train?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did the Jeannette Club own its own bus?
[SPEAKER_04]: What kind of a bus was it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Ford?
[SPEAKER_04]: That's pretty early for buses, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: 1927?
[SPEAKER_04]: Didn't break down on the road at all, or?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: What about hotels?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you stay in pretty nice places in the middle of Atlantic Lake, or?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not Youngstown.
[SPEAKER_03]: Stupidville?
[SPEAKER_03]: How hard do you find reading?
[SPEAKER_03]: Janesville?
[SPEAKER_04]: Janesville in the lake?
[SPEAKER_03]: San Pedro?
[SPEAKER_03]: San Pedro.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you're taking care of all of us.
[SPEAKER_04]: What kind of ballparks did they have in the middle of Atlantic Lake?
[SPEAKER_04]: They were pretty good.
[SPEAKER_04]: Were they?
[SPEAKER_04]: Dressing rooms pretty up-to-date?
[SPEAKER_05]: They were pretty up-to-date, but it was all right.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you draw very big crowds?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about night baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you play any night baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Was night baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: It hadn't started, I guess, in the Mid-Atlantic League.
[SPEAKER_04]: But how about in the New York League?
[SPEAKER_04]: Were they playing night ball up there yet?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Towards the end, he was playing night ball.
[SPEAKER_05]: I played night ball up in the New York League.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you were later on, you played night ball.
[SPEAKER_04]: Springfield, maybe.
[SPEAKER_04]: I went back to Springfield in the Mid-Atlantic League.
[SPEAKER_04]: They probably had lights.
[SPEAKER_04]: Would you like to pitch under the lights?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I didn't care.
[SPEAKER_04]: You think it affects the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't like it, either.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like when they played a day, mostly under.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said that's what hurt his eyes.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they didn't have the right kind of light that you couldn't see where the ball was coming from.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lighting was pretty poor, wasn't it, in those early years?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, the first couple of years, it was, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't like it?
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't like that ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: You said you didn't think it was nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Baseball would last, because the way it was set up, it was too hard to see the ball.
[SPEAKER_04]: You think that there's been one reason why batting averages have been going down?
[SPEAKER_04]: You suppose night baseball is the reason?
[SPEAKER_04]: One of the reasons?
[SPEAKER_04]: They don't hit it well.
[SPEAKER_04]: But maybe it's the night.
[SPEAKER_04]: The rice is the reason.
[SPEAKER_04]: And they can't see.
[SPEAKER_04]: But they have to work.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, this year, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wonder how tight Cobb would have done under the lights.
[SPEAKER_03]: Probably only did about 362.
[SPEAKER_04]: 367.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they bunt much on you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Batters try to bunt you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you have any trouble fielding?
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd you field?
[SPEAKER_04]: I fielded good.
[SPEAKER_03]: You ever pick any up barehanded?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll check.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have a hard job.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you're pretty good at it.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you like living in Brooklyn when you went up there?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you live in Brooklyn or in New York?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you stay in a hotel there or a rooming house?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that's where he stayed.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't stay here, then.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just took the picture here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember he said he stayed in a place with old people.
[SPEAKER_01]: A rooming house, you stayed.
[SPEAKER_01]: In Brooklyn, you stayed in a rooming house.
[SPEAKER_05]: I was the only one there.
[SPEAKER_05]: What about this picture here?
[SPEAKER_05]: He stayed in front of a hotel or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh my God.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever box stop much?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever play against any black players?
[SPEAKER_03]: It's been wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you think, Jimmy, just a bit?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: But at Barstow, I think a lot of times they like to replace some of the black teams at Barstow.
[SPEAKER_04]: In fact, that's how some of our information about black players is gotten from white players who played against them at Barstow, because their records are so incomplete.
[SPEAKER_04]: So this is one thing we've tried to ask about, hopefully we can hear about some.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, what colored players did you play against?
[SPEAKER_03]: What colored players did you play against?
[SPEAKER_03]: What?
[SPEAKER_03]: Anywhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anytime.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played...
[SPEAKER_03]: There were some big stars there, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Green... Green camp.
[SPEAKER_03]: Green camp?
[SPEAKER_03]: Green camp you played for, wasn't there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Excuse me, you played against Satchel Paige.
[SPEAKER_03]: Satchel Paige and, uh, he was from the, played with the Homestead Grays.
[SPEAKER_03]: These are big names of the colored men that you played against.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what was that other club, Josh Gibson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Josh Gibson's in the Hall of Fame now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitch to Josh Gibson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what's that other guy's name?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was younger.
[SPEAKER_03]: Played for the Huffington State Jays.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_03]: Lucky something.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lucky Jones or Lucky Smith?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a well-known team.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitch on the Huffington State Jays.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitch right at him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pitch up.
[SPEAKER_03]: They did pretty good, my buddies.
[SPEAKER_03]: They got me in the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got me in the Hall of Fame though.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Hall of Fame took them in.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a little biggish.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to be rich.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never played professional ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ben.
[SPEAKER_03]: We don't have any records either.
[SPEAKER_04]: The records, you can't really.
He's not right from Cleveland, then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, we don't want Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I visited there and I was shocked.
Ben.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, uh, who did you, uh, room with with the Dodgers?
[SPEAKER_04]: You have a roommate on the road?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember him?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember a shot.
[SPEAKER_04]: When you went on the road, didn't they put you together with somebody?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't remember a shot.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, uh, how'd you like those long train rides?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember a lot.
[SPEAKER_03]: What would you do?
[SPEAKER_03]: What would the players do?
[SPEAKER_03]: Play time?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know, but they've got the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: They've got the ball, whatever.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have a favorite ballpark?
[SPEAKER_03]: What time is it?
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Baker Bowl?
[SPEAKER_03]: Have any stories about Baker Bowl?
[SPEAKER_03]: I know it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Baker Bowl.
[SPEAKER_03]: We've got a real short right field spread.
[SPEAKER_03]: Philadelphia there.
[SPEAKER_03]: You just couldn't let up at all.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, who was, uh, you're up with the Boston Braves for a little while, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: One day.
[SPEAKER_03]: It says here you lost two games.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you lose two games in one day?
[SPEAKER_03]: I lost one game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: One day we were on the pitch and it was snowing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was afraid to go up to Boston radio, wait before we could get out to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: Your arm just got stiff?
[SPEAKER_03]: Your arm got stiffened up maybe?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got out of bed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was the manager?
[SPEAKER_03]: George, uh... Was Stallings still there?
[SPEAKER_03]: George Stallings?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know any good George Stallings stories?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was kept away from him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was tough, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what I heard.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had some kind of a guitar.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's always nicely dressed, though, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: He always had a shirt, coat, hat.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever manage?
[SPEAKER_04]: I never worked that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never worked that kind of job.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't care about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Later years, you managed.
[SPEAKER_03]: We're steel.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've had a couple of experiences.
I can't be done on that one.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dad, you managed the steel.
[SPEAKER_01]: The steel team.
[SPEAKER_01]: You managed to win at the Steel Baseball team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's ever.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, 35.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that on there, too?
[SPEAKER_03]: Doesn't say managed, but he says he was 35 or 37.
[SPEAKER_03]: He managed and played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they do that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did your manager not play?
[SPEAKER_01]: You managed and played.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we're...
[SPEAKER_03]: Playing manager there at work?
[SPEAKER_03]: You managed and played.
[SPEAKER_03]: He worked.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you work in the steel mill?
[SPEAKER_03]: I worked every day.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you have to work really?
[SPEAKER_04]: It was just kind of an excuse to have you there to manage the team.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did most of the players work in the plant?
[SPEAKER_03]: You must have worked in the wintertime.
[SPEAKER_01]: My father had a work station.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure you worked in the mill in the wintertime anyhow.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know you did.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where's the steel?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where's the steel you worked in the mill?
[SPEAKER_03]: Probably in the winter.
[SPEAKER_03]: You worked in the mill in the summer, you played in the fall.
[SPEAKER_03]: Back when you were in the big leagues, what did you do in the off-season?
[SPEAKER_04]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_03]: You weren't allowed to do anything?
[SPEAKER_03]: Didn't you go hunting?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or fishing?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said you weren't allowed to work.
[SPEAKER_03]: The club did?
[SPEAKER_03]: Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said don't work.
[SPEAKER_03]: What I remember is, in the winters, you always said you had to take care of your arm.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't strain his arm or anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd walk and play ball practice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He kept his arm in shape.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right?
[SPEAKER_03]: He doesn't know that we're here.
[SPEAKER_03]: How many miles would it be?
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd run a few miles every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to walk to Pittsburgh from here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Things like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's not from Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't know this area.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm sorry.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm learning.
[SPEAKER_03]: We used to have this dirty spot.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's really nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's beautiful.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were really proud of our Steelers.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were a tough team.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you still like baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you follow it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't you get a little impatient with some of these players today and all the money they make?
[SPEAKER_03]: She ain't got to work.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd be out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd be working.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd show up and out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd show up, Joe, and he'd make shoes.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd get it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: They'd make a little scratch, and they'd take them out at the gate.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a little thing.
I'd save $150,000.
[SPEAKER_04]: What about the umpiring in your days?
[SPEAKER_04]: Were the umpires pretty good, do you think?
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was a good umpire?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: Clamps?
[SPEAKER_03]: No clamps, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, that's what we've been talking about for about 40 years.
[SPEAKER_03]: New York, New York, because they, you know, like, there are three of those streets.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's all they call it.
[SPEAKER_03]: One, one, one year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, they call it the Blackfoot Street.
[SPEAKER_03]: They call it the Blackfoot Street.
[SPEAKER_03]: They don't want to call it that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, apparently, you know, three years from now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember reading that article.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't say it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He got over there and he said, shut that door and knock it over.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just read their article and that's the only time he was thrown out of the ballpark according to that article at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they said someone on the bench called him Catfish or something.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can't see Catfish or something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he looked over, and it was coming from the direction where he was sitting, but there was other men there.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he put his eye to the game, and then he decided, well, I better put the other one's eye to the right around here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had you said it?
[SPEAKER_03]: But you got mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got fined, and the other was just going to put it out of the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what they said.
[SPEAKER_01]: $10 was the fine.
[SPEAKER_03]: You hadn't called him that, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was somebody else.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't say anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: What are you going to do?
[SPEAKER_04]: Were the umpires in the Federal League any good?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: Remember an umpire named Manasaw in the Federal League?
[SPEAKER_04]: Manasaw?
[SPEAKER_04]: What name?
[SPEAKER_03]: I've been out here a year.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was just one year, I think.
[SPEAKER_04]: You think the umpires are fair, in your experience?
[SPEAKER_04]: They really try to do a good, honest job?
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you ever know Tim Hurst?
[SPEAKER_04]: Any stories about him?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he got kicked out of the American League.
[SPEAKER_03]: He punched somebody in the eye.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Billy Evans?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you know him?
[SPEAKER_03]: American League?
[SPEAKER_03]: You probably didn't know the American Leaguers very well, did you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, in spring training, you probably saw a stunt by the coach.
[SPEAKER_04]: Does anything stand out in your mind as your greatest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Any one thing?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know if it's true.
[SPEAKER_04]: Winning some big game or pitching some great game, nothing stands out to me, especially.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember any real funny incidents or some real funny things happening in baseball?
[SPEAKER_03]: Funny things are always happening.
[SPEAKER_04]: What if anything stood out to you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Like some crazy plays, you know?
[SPEAKER_03]: And of course, she didn't come.
[SPEAKER_03]: It probably comes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they say, is this a picture of a table or a chair?
[SPEAKER_03]: Is this a picture of a chair?
[SPEAKER_03]: Their basement never moved.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is this a picture of a table?
[SPEAKER_03]: They shortstopped.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is how they came up with their mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, then, from there, it's just a question of, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where it comes to it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was what, 73 or 74?
[SPEAKER_03]: 72.
[SPEAKER_03]: 72, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a Marine, exceptionally good at it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a New Yorker.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a New Yorker, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a baseball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: What?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a 95-degree shooter.
[SPEAKER_03]: With a forked shield in his hat.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was down at the...
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they feed you pretty well?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Morrison did.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll tell Morrison I had a big, fine steak.
Yeah?
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Brooklyn?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they give you so much money for a day or did you have to eat at a certain place?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did they give you the money and you could go eat where you wanted to?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they give you enough money to eat well?
[SPEAKER_03]: I think two years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Two years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because every time he gets this movie, he gets it.
[SPEAKER_03]: For what, a day?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't have a big supper?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what you thought people were.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you find the water to go out.
Smoking?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Blasting somewhere, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Way down this way, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Calvary?
[SPEAKER_05]: Cincinnati?
[SPEAKER_03]: Cleveland?
No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Up in New York State.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, New York State.
[SPEAKER_03]: And?
[SPEAKER_04]: Binghamton.
[SPEAKER_03]: Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah, yeah, Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who would you play with then?
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what they used to do in them days?
[SPEAKER_02]: They used to hire them to just play one game, and he'd go into a different name.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did they call that now?
[SPEAKER_03]: That sneaky trick.
[SPEAKER_04]: We've heard some interesting stories about that.
[SPEAKER_04]: And we pitched just for the day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hired to pitch for the day in different cities.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jack said you were hired to pitch for the day, for the team, just for that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now what was that called?
[SPEAKER_03]: In the past.
[SPEAKER_03]: Independent.
[SPEAKER_03]: What team did you play for when you went up there to Buffalo?
[SPEAKER_03]: Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_03]: They must have had a lot of money because of what they did for it that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He only pitched the one game there.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's where he got the gold watch, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the gold watch he gave to his other son-in-law.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't remember what it said.
[SPEAKER_02]: The watch was given to you by the Federal League, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's the Federal League.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was supposed to be the most outstanding ball player they had on that team.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, pitching, because he won a lot of games.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it was given to him by the public of Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_03]: people from the audience, I guess, presented him with this big blue watch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was this Donald's presentation?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, there's a Federal League ball I thought you were going to say.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's one with 1914 on it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Here, Federal League baseball, even.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's amazing, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: I like his earrings.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, gosh.
[SPEAKER_03]: The whole time.
Oh.
[SPEAKER_04]: Let me read these names into the tape here.
[SPEAKER_04]: This says Lynchburg, Virginia, 1914.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is your Federal League file here.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's got Lynchburg, Virginia on it.
[SPEAKER_04]: What would that mean?
[SPEAKER_04]: Were you training down there?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, here are the names.
[SPEAKER_04]: Gessler, manager.
[SPEAKER_04]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_04]: H. Gessler.
[SPEAKER_04]: Gessler.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't remember him.
[SPEAKER_04]: Lewis, second base.
[SPEAKER_04]: Jack Lewis.
[SPEAKER_04]: Barger or Barger.
[SPEAKER_04]: Barger.
[SPEAKER_04]: C. Barger.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: W. Dixon.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_04]: What was the W, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_04]: Williams.
[SPEAKER_04]: Adams.
[SPEAKER_04]: W. Adams.
[SPEAKER_04]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Roberts.
[SPEAKER_04]: E. Clare.
[SPEAKER_04]: Boy, a lot of pitchers there.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had eight pitchers.
[SPEAKER_04]: Henderson.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Kamnitz.
[SPEAKER_04]: Is that Howard Kamnitz?
[SPEAKER_04]: He played with the Pirates.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a big pitcher, wasn't he, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_04]: He must have been a 20-game winner.
[SPEAKER_03]: Walker, a picture, and then yourself.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then over here is Bradley, McDonald, and Scott.
[SPEAKER_04]: W. Scott, shortstop, says.
[SPEAKER_04]: Lennox.
[SPEAKER_04]: Third place.
[SPEAKER_04]: D. Jones.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's not Davy Jones, is it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boston somewhere, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_05]: No.
[SPEAKER_05]: Way down this way, in the hot.
[SPEAKER_05]: Columbus?
[SPEAKER_05]: No.
[SPEAKER_05]: Cincinnati?
[SPEAKER_05]: Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_05]: No.
[SPEAKER_05]: It's up New York State.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it's New York State.
[SPEAKER_01]: And?
[SPEAKER_05]: Where?
[SPEAKER_01]: Binghamton.
[SPEAKER_05]: Where, where?
[SPEAKER_01]: Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who would you play with then?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know what they used to do in them days?
[SPEAKER_02]: They used to hire them for just play one game and he'd go under a different name.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did they call that now?
[SPEAKER_01]: That sneaky trick.
[SPEAKER_04]: We've heard some interesting stories about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were pitched just for the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hired to pitch for the day in different cities.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack said you were hired to pitch for the day, for the team, just for that game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now what was that called?
[SPEAKER_02]: Independence.
[SPEAKER_01]: Independence.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now who, let's get this, what team did you play for when you went up there to Buffalo, do you know?
[SPEAKER_02]: Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that was, uh, they must've had a lot of money because, uh, what all they did for him that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he, you only pitched the one game there?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where he got the gold watch too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the gold watch he gave to his other son-in-law.
[SPEAKER_02]: The watch was given to you by the Federal League, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, that's the Federal League.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it had given to him, he was supposed to be the most outstanding ball player they had on that team.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, pitching, I guess he won a lot of games.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was given to him by the public of Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_02]: People from the audience, I guess, presented him with this big little watch.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was this all the balls that was up there, Jack?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's a Federal League ball icon even, is there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was one with 1914 on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here, Federal League Baseball, even.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's amazing, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: I like the Xerox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, God.
[SPEAKER_04]: That whole sign up.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then these other ones say National League.
[SPEAKER_04]: Let me read these names into the tape here.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is the...
[SPEAKER_04]: Uh, the, it says Lynchburg, Virginia, 1914.
[SPEAKER_04]: What, uh, here's your Federal League ball here.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's got Lynchburg, Virginia on it.
[SPEAKER_04]: What would that mean?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you know?
[SPEAKER_04]: Were you training down there?
[SPEAKER_05]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, here are the names, uh, Gessler, manager.
[SPEAKER_04]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_04]: H. Gessler.
[SPEAKER_05]: Gessler.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05]: I remember him.
[SPEAKER_04]: Lewis, second base.
[SPEAKER_05]: Jack Lewis.
[SPEAKER_04]: Jack Lewis.
[SPEAKER_04]: Barger or Barger.
[SPEAKER_05]: Barger.
[SPEAKER_04]: C. Barger.
[SPEAKER_05]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: W. Dixon.
[SPEAKER_04]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_04]: What was the W?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_04]: William or?
[SPEAKER_04]: Walter.
[SPEAKER_04]: Walter Dixon.
[SPEAKER_04]: Adams.
[SPEAKER_05]: W. Adams.
[SPEAKER_04]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_05]: Roberts.
[SPEAKER_04]: Roberts, pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: E. Clare, pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Boy, you had a lot of pitchers there.
[SPEAKER_04]: You had eight pitchers.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Kamnitz.
[SPEAKER_04]: Is that Howard Kamnitz?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He later was with the Pirates.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a big pitcher, wasn't he, with you?
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He must have been a 20-game winner.
[SPEAKER_05]: I guess he won more than 20 games.
[SPEAKER_05]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_05]: Big, big.
[SPEAKER_05]: Walker.
[SPEAKER_04]: Walker.
[SPEAKER_01]: A pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then yourself.
[SPEAKER_04]: And then over here is Bradley, McDonald, and Scott, W. Scott, shortstop says, remember him?
[SPEAKER_04]: And Lennox, Lennox, third base, D. Jones,
[SPEAKER_04]: That's not Davy Jones, is it?
[SPEAKER_01]: It sounds like Davy Jones' locker.
[SPEAKER_04]: It wasn't Davy Jones.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, yeah, Detroit Outfielder.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was 90, or I guess he passed away a couple years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: That could be, that age.
[SPEAKER_04]: But I didn't know that Davy Jones jumped, though.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oakes, he was a center fielder.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Savage.
[SPEAKER_05]: He was a men's fielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: This would be on the picture.
[SPEAKER_05]: He was in that building.
[SPEAKER_05]: Matt's?
[SPEAKER_03]: Matt's.
[SPEAKER_05]: He was right there I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: And Ream.
[SPEAKER_04]: Or Ream.
[SPEAKER_04]: C. Ream.
[SPEAKER_04]: Or Ream's.
[SPEAKER_04]: Boy, isn't that amazing?
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe they weren't all in the same time.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's an historic ball.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's nothing like that anywhere, probably.
[SPEAKER_04]: Here, Cyrus Reams, R-E-G-A-M-S. How about Smallwood?
[SPEAKER_04]: Percy Smallwood, trainer.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's the marathon runner, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, trainer.
[SPEAKER_05]: E. Margan, or Margar.
[SPEAKER_05]: Margan.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_04]: See, isn't that wonderful?
[SPEAKER_04]: With Gilmore's signature.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever meet Gilmore?
[SPEAKER_04]: The league president?
[SPEAKER_04]: Gilmore.
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_02]: The president.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, that's the team president.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to say, this is an American League ball and a National League ball.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't know they had two different... Yeah, I think Spalding is a National League and reaches the American League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they say what they're made of.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spalding is a National League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dusty Dodges.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I think of what we didn't have,
[SPEAKER_04]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's forever the case.
[SPEAKER_04]: Could you go ahead and tell us a little bit about the family then, while the tape is on here, about your father and mother when they met and what life was like growing up in a baseball family?
[SPEAKER_02]: On this street here, when they built, he moved on this street in 1915.
[SPEAKER_01]: He bought, built a house the year they got married.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nice little white bungalow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we want to pick it up.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they moved on Hilson Avenue in Brentwood here in 1915.
[SPEAKER_02]: The year you got married.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the year he got married.
[SPEAKER_04]: And um, there was a,
[SPEAKER_02]: They still had the gas lamps, you know, the street lights on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, and the street was a dirt street.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Mrs. Knetzler used to say how the old lamplighter used to come down and put the light on and then come down, you know, and take it off.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was his job.
[SPEAKER_02]: The man went around the town and put the lights off and on.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he only had two children, two girls, Rita and Bernice.
[SPEAKER_04]: When were you born?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1922.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Rita was born 19... Yeah, that's your sister.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1917.
[SPEAKER_01]: She lives in California.
[SPEAKER_01]: He only became a great-grandfather for the first time at 89 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that amazing?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Hawaii, his grandson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Grandson was in the service in Hawaii.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's your nephew?
[SPEAKER_04]: Sisters.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, your nephew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Congratulations.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05]: My school teachers.
[SPEAKER_05]: Oh, fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: My sisters had four children and they're all teaching.
[SPEAKER_05]: Some are still fighting for more and more and more.
[SPEAKER_01]: Are they going on to more schooling?
[SPEAKER_01]: You know by that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knows being a college professor.
[SPEAKER_02]: About 20 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: I teach history.
[SPEAKER_02]: I like history.
[SPEAKER_04]: I like baseball history.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm fascinated by baseball history.
[SPEAKER_04]: My bedroom is filled with baseball books going back to the 1870s.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, how wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: His baseball goes back to the 1870s.
[SPEAKER_04]: Baseball record books I've got going back to 1878.
[SPEAKER_04]: I have a Spalding guide for 1878.
[SPEAKER_04]: I have a baseball guide, either a Richard Spalding guide, for every year since then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, how wonderful.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't have both guys every year, but I have one and the other.
[SPEAKER_02]: Have Grandpap tell you about the gloves, how thin the gloves were.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's hard to believe, you know, with no padding at all practically in the glove.
[SPEAKER_01]: They liked it that way, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: They wanted to make a pocket in the glove.
[SPEAKER_02]: Grandpap used to tell them something, how these baseball, these writers, newspaper fellas, how they used to destroy a lot of ballplayers, how they used to get them all pepped up.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, they bring them up too quick, you know, writing the paper, how they're going to do this and they're going to do that, and if the poor fella doesn't reach that goal, it makes him look bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says how a lot of writers ruin a lot of fellas coming up.
[SPEAKER_04]: Were the writers pretty fair to you, would you say, baseball writers, or how did they treat you?
[SPEAKER_05]: Well, I never saw them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I understand.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you used to like what they wrote about you, Grandpa?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you used to like what the writers, did you ever disagree with the writers?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I left them go.
[SPEAKER_02]: You left them go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of the things were nice, by what we have here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever see him pitch?
[SPEAKER_02]: I never know any writers.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was pretty young.
[SPEAKER_02]: I seen him pitch when he was 72.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he, would you believe it or not, he could
[SPEAKER_02]: He threw the ball so hard at 72, if he didn't watch the way you caught the ball, you'd stow to your fingers.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's hard to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hardly practiced.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hurt your hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitched three innings.
[SPEAKER_02]: He could throw the ball that hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: 97 degree temperature.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was so terrible.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a really, the hot, hot kind of weather.
[SPEAKER_02]: He received that day a big birthday cake with a complete baseball field on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's received that from the mayor of Pittsburgh, as Mayor Lawrence.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's, and, uh, and, uh, what's his other guy's name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Big ball player was his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pye Traynor.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pye Traynor gave him a, uh, presented him with another birthday cake the same day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got two cakes that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember him and I, Grandpa was the only, him and I were the only one who went to the ball game.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, uh, cause she was expecting, you know, a couple of weeks or so.
[SPEAKER_02]: So anyway,
[SPEAKER_02]: The whole back of the car had these two huge birthday cakes like this here.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't know it was going to turn out so nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't know it was going to be that nice.
[SPEAKER_04]: Your mother didn't care for baseball much.
[SPEAKER_04]: Not that much, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was a homemaker.
[SPEAKER_05]: She thought mother's place was in the home with her children.
[SPEAKER_01]: I still have them.
[SPEAKER_05]: The little players, pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: My mother was a strict type of person and believed a woman's place was in the home.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did she ever go to the games?
[SPEAKER_01]: She traveled with him only a little bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: In Shamokin.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the only place... That's professional.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were married until she was in the Federal Agency.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe the women didn't do that then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe they didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the other players take their wives with them then?
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah, some did, some didn't.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some of the wives were much more interested in others.
[SPEAKER_01]: I bet she wasn't that interested, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some were just really excited about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some packed up the kids and took them.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: And some would never miss a game, and oh, how they would worry when their husband would be pitching, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some would sit with the players' wives, and this one woman, Mrs. Jess Haines.
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: She always sat with the players' wives, but, you know, I always want to say Yablonski.
[SPEAKER_04]: Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_00]: She wouldn't sit with the players' wives.
[SPEAKER_00]: She'd go up and sit in the stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if they said anything, she'd say, he's great, don't you say anything about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Get all excited.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, she was with them in one
[SPEAKER_01]: the small town where you played and she said that they were walking down the street and she said the girls come up to him and said, Elmer, Elmer, the wonderful game you pitched and pushed her right aside and made such a fuss over him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He used to be kind of embarrassed.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a quiet kind of man.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did she keep the scrapbooks?
[SPEAKER_04]: A lot of the wives kept the scrapbooks.
[SPEAKER_04]: Or did you do that?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess she kept them, but I can't imagine her keeping them in this condition.
[SPEAKER_01]: The younger, as younger girls, my sister and I put them in the book.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we're going to have to make a better one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I, he has his other daughters, children are all, were real polished, educated, real educated.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I always, when I went, they live in California.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I was there visiting them, I says, one of you kids ought to write his memoirs in baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Write his whole life history.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I met this one right over your head.
[SPEAKER_04]: I think that would be wonderful to write a book about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he tell you about him meeting Teddy Roosevelt and President Taft?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell the story.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who were you with then, Grandpa?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that with Brooklyn in 1910?
[SPEAKER_02]: You met, who was that, President Taft?
[SPEAKER_02]: And then he met Teddy Roosevelt also at the White House.
[SPEAKER_02]: That must have been 1909.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when he met Teddy Roosevelt.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he can recall how President Taft was a big heavy man.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he liked Teddy Roosevelt.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says what a nice man he was, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, Taft was quite a baseball fan.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a baseball fan.
[SPEAKER_04]: And they'd send Ben Johnson, which sent Roosevelt season passes to all the games, and he never went.
[SPEAKER_04]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_06]: But Taft was out there all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He is.
[SPEAKER_06]: Taft's brother became the part owner of the Chicago Cubs later on.
[SPEAKER_05]: He's from where?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's a great Cincinnati family there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: You were at Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: What I heard was that he liked the smaller
[SPEAKER_01]: teams, the smaller leagues, what would you call them?
[SPEAKER_01]: The minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_01]: The industrial leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because they treated the players so wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Terrans just loved the team so and went to all the games and made the players feel good because they followed the team so.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he enjoyed that all.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wished he would have
[SPEAKER_01]: really stayed and lived in Shemokin, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was offered so many things in Shemokin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Shemokin?
[SPEAKER_01]: Shemokin, you were offered so many things that if you would have stayed and lived there, because they treated their players so nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't somebody want to give you a bowling alley?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that the time?
[SPEAKER_02]: He got a lot of gifts because, you know, we were winning the games and things.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never took anything from anybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not that way, but I mean, they liked you so well then.
[SPEAKER_02]: He means he wasn't bribed.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wouldn't be bribed.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was always honest.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as I said, he didn't drink whenever they, well, one night my mother tells this story that they played a game somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what team you were with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe you'll remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he called up and said, I won't be home tonight.
[SPEAKER_01]: I won't be in till tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said, gee, that's funny.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the next day he always said, Oh, there's the, the weather's too bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the mountain roads and the rain was up in the mountains somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the next day he told her that the men had, they won the game and the men were all drinking.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's why you didn't, you didn't want to come home with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as I said, if they won the game, they'd all go out for drinking and he would, they would buy him ice cream.
[SPEAKER_01]: He would get big dishes of ice cream or gallons of ice cream.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't they buy you the ice cream?
[SPEAKER_01]: And they would get the drinks.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a big steak eater.
[SPEAKER_01]: He would get...
[SPEAKER_05]: I wouldn't go...
[SPEAKER_02]: Really?
[SPEAKER_02]: The men that were drinking.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he's never smoked a coffee.
[SPEAKER_01]: He only smokes, no, pipe.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't smoke in your baseball playing days, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't drink or smoke in your baseball playing days.
[SPEAKER_01]: He only started to smoke the pipe afterwards.
[SPEAKER_05]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he likes his pipe.
[SPEAKER_04]: What did you do after baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Anything particular?
[SPEAKER_02]: He worked 16 years for Lawrence.
[SPEAKER_02]: and that is the Watchman.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a department store.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: How do you know that?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about zeroing in on a store?
[SPEAKER_05]: Thank you for one for government.
[SPEAKER_02]: Someone told us that a grandfather's watchman can walk 20 miles a day, six days a week.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there's
[SPEAKER_02]: And he went from there, he was playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: From baseball into that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we have pictures of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know which railroad it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_02]: He finally got that job there.
[SPEAKER_02]: The only way he could make any money is to work 13 hours a day.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'd like to look through that scrapbook now.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm turning the tape off.
[SPEAKER_04]: I wanted to ask your husband about that.
[SPEAKER_04]: What's your work?
[SPEAKER_02]: I work in the Mester Machine Company.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know Pearl Mester?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: We build the rolls.
[SPEAKER_02]: We make a roll fund.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you know Pearl?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: We make a complete steel mill where I work.
[SPEAKER_02]: We make the steel mills.
[SPEAKER_02]: We do about 70% of our work is done outside of the United States.
[SPEAKER_02]: We build mills for all over the world.
[SPEAKER_04]: Are you from Brentwood?
[SPEAKER_04]: No, I'm from Munhall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which is right next to Homestead, where they had the Homestead Grave.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it's only about five or six miles from here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, how did you two get together?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we went out to the dance.
[SPEAKER_04]: You dance?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I like to dance.
[SPEAKER_01]: What would you call it?
[SPEAKER_02]: And when were you married now?
[SPEAKER_02]: 1951.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, we have you beat by a year.
[SPEAKER_04]: We beat you by a year.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh!
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm 25 years old.
[SPEAKER_04]: You're in for a 25th this year.
[SPEAKER_02]: You have 25 years at the Mester Machine Company.
[SPEAKER_04]: What did your father do?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a carpenter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He worked at the Mester Machine Company too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Is Pearl Mester from around here?
[SPEAKER_02]: She lived here in West Homestead.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was only married to
[SPEAKER_02]: one of the Mestas for about 16 months.
[SPEAKER_02]: I know the history of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He committed suicide.
[SPEAKER_02]: She got all her wealth, her father was a big, in Oklahoma he had a big, the oil wells, he was a, what do they call it, a tycoon in oil wells.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she's really connected with the Mestas?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, but she lived, when her first got married, they lived in Olmstead here.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's pretty interesting.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they have a great big mansion down there, where she lived.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, you're on.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, you were going to a family.
[SPEAKER_00]: Identify yourself.
[SPEAKER_04]: I know, but what's happened?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, and mommy gets murdered, and we're back at the motel.
[SPEAKER_00]: We have to fill up half a tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he explain, uh, Jack explained how he worked at the foundry?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: For Pearl Mesta?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, this is very, very difficult work, uh, because it's all handwork.
[SPEAKER_00]: Putting those steel mills together.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he finally had to join a health spa because about five years ago it was getting too, we decided he was getting too old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Robinson, the son-in-law.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he goes and works out.
[SPEAKER_00]: John Joseph was his real name.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he goes and works out two or three times a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't really work out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sits in the spa, sits in the whirlpool bath and everything to get the aches out of his muscles.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did they have, three children?
[SPEAKER_00]: a boy, a girl, and a little girl.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the other daughter has the four children.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're the ones that are all educated.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've all had at least five years of college and some more.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they really are so wrapped up in their education that they really haven't had much time for baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were a little put out when Grandpa gave his watch that he got from the Federal League to his other son-in-law
[SPEAKER_00]: They were.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they know that you've had more college than that, but you're human.
[SPEAKER_00]: You are.
[SPEAKER_00]: And let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: They won't let him watch the hockey games because they're, they won't let grandpa watch the hockey games because they're afraid he'll get too excited.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't miss one of the Pittsburgh, uh, one of the football games on television this year.
[SPEAKER_06]: Okay, talk a little bit about how Mr. Knetzer struck you.
[SPEAKER_06]: The record books are wrong.
[SPEAKER_06]: I have his birthday wrong, by the way.
[SPEAKER_06]: They have 1887.
[SPEAKER_06]: That's 1885, so he's 89, not 87.
[SPEAKER_06]: Yeah, he's 89.
[SPEAKER_06]: The record the encyclopedia has, he's born 87.
[SPEAKER_06]: And that's a date I gave, and right away I was corrected.
[SPEAKER_06]: So that's where I got that date from.
[SPEAKER_06]: Describe him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I guess up until September or October of this year,
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in great shape.
[SPEAKER_04]: We're coming in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well he was, but he's lost 40 pounds in about three months.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's quite upset about this.
[SPEAKER_04]: Hard to picture him as a big rugged guy we saw in the pictures, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well you know that picture taken of him in front of the bulletin board at Horns?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was over 60 when that picture was taken.
[SPEAKER_00]: because he was over 60 when he went to work for Horns as a security guard.
[SPEAKER_06]: Yeah, he's a beautiful physical specimen.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he flew out to California in September by himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did he have his stroke?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's just had it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the hospital for three weeks out there.
[SPEAKER_04]: When you say just, you mean this last fall?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, this last fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the summer, you know, they told us how he had cut the
[SPEAKER_00]: 150 feet of hitch, and that's a lot of hitches, you well know.
[SPEAKER_00]: All by hand.
[SPEAKER_06]: He needs an electric trimmer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he went out to California by himself in September.
[SPEAKER_00]: And while he was out there, he had this stroke.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the hospital for three weeks.
[SPEAKER_06]: He visited his other daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He visited his other daughter.
[SPEAKER_06]: Rita.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they said that, uh, the doctor said there was really no hope for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was either a nursing home, or they could take him home if they wanted to.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the daughter said she would take him home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just sat around the house, and I guess he just stayed in bed and cried because he had no control over his right side and that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't talk, and he wanted to come home to Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so his son-in-law went out one Friday
[SPEAKER_00]: and flew back with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had to get him on a wheelchair.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jack?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Jack.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was in a wheelchair and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't think he'd make it at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the doctor said there wasn't much hope.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when he got home, he started to pick up.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she said if she had told her sister that he acted the way he did tonight, his sister wouldn't believe it, Rita.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because even
[SPEAKER_00]: Teresa is it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or Bernice?
[SPEAKER_06]: I think Bernice.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bernice was amazed at how he held up tonight and how he could ask questions.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was quite surprised.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this 40 pounds that he's lost in September has just sort of upset them and upset him because he doesn't like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he has never, he's never touched liquor in his life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Won't have anything to do with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started smoking his pipe after he was out of baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: All he lived for was his training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when the kids were little and he was playing baseball, he ran 10 miles every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get up in the morning and go out and run 10 miles every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when he started working at Warren's, he was walking
[SPEAKER_00]: 30 miles in a day, and he was over 60 then, at all the check-in places as a watchman.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was hard to get jobs then, apparently, whenever this was that he started working there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was lucky that he got in here as a security guard, and the only way he couldn't make enough money was to work 13 hours a day, six days a week, and that's what he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: which I thought was quite...
[SPEAKER_06]: Horns is a department store?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, it's a famous department store.
[SPEAKER_06]: I'm sorry, but I want to get it clear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Horns.
[SPEAKER_06]: Four years from now, they might not know this.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Horns is a big department store and they have branches all over.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think there's one in Wheeling.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, when you mention Horns, you know it's Pittsburgh, or you mention Pittsburgh, you know it's Horns.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he knew Rooney, the Rooney boys, from the time they were little.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when Three Rivers Stadium opened,
[SPEAKER_00]: Art Rooney gave him a personally conducted tour and because it upset him to sit in the grandstand or something, he got to use Rooney's private box to see the game.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, I interviewed Art Rooney.
[SPEAKER_06]: He played professional baseball.
[SPEAKER_06]: Well.
[SPEAKER_06]: What did your brother do, too, when he became a priest?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Mr. Knapser, his brother played baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says he tried to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He pitched for a few, tried to pitch for a few teams around here.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then one manager got a hold of him, who wanted him to twist his arm, twist his hand when he threw the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this ruined his arm completely, though it wasn't any good to begin with.
[SPEAKER_04]: Tell now about what happened out in the picture taping as an observer.
[SPEAKER_06]: Put that on the tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is my poppykins is going frantic and trying to take pictures?
[SPEAKER_06]: We quit the interview about 10 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_06]: And I wanted to get some pictures or look at the scrapbooks and things.
[SPEAKER_06]: And so the Robinsons who was
[SPEAKER_06]: nice and as kind as they could be about this.
[SPEAKER_06]: They just took us in like old friends.
[SPEAKER_06]: She escorted us into the dining room, or me, to look at their stuff she had laid out in there.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then there wasn't really that much, but there were some nice things, some long, these teen pictures in Exposition Park, the old Federal
[SPEAKER_06]: It was the old Pittsburgh Pirate Park in the old days.
[SPEAKER_06]: And then when Forbes Field was built, they moved in there.
[SPEAKER_06]: And when the feds came along, they must have renovated Exposition Park.
[SPEAKER_06]: I remember reading about Exposition Park.
[SPEAKER_06]: And we've got a couple of panoramic pictures of this, which they have, and one of which is a poster, which I have here.
[SPEAKER_06]: Let me take and try to have a copy in about three sections.
[SPEAKER_06]: The problem was trying to, knowing what to copy or what to photograph with my little trilex camera.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pintex.
[SPEAKER_06]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_06]: Well, okay.
[SPEAKER_06]: The film is trilex.
[SPEAKER_06]: But you as an observer, you can tell.